<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Private on Tomas Tech Lab</title>
    <link>https://tomastechlab.com/tags/private/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Private on Tomas Tech Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 20:39:03 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://tomastechlab.com/tags/private/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why No Comments</title>
      <link>https://tomastechlab.com/posts/why-no-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 20:39:03 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tomastechlab.com/posts/why-no-comments/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This blog ist just my little outlet for the time when I fell like writing something.&#xA;Its not really meant for others to read but its online anyway as there might be someone on this&#xA;lovely blue ball in the universe that might find some particular detail interesting enogh to read about it&#xA;on my blog.&#xA;Besides that I dont really expect a lot of traffic on here.&#xA;Heck, I dont even have userstats or analytics in any way for this site.&#xA;Sure I could aggregate the data from my server logs but thats more of a tedious task on a bored winter night or something.&#xA;Thats the exact same reason why I dont have comments enabled on here.&#xA;Its not that the blogging platform I use isn&amp;rsquo;t capable of it. Its just a flag I decided to turn off on purpose.&#xA;I dont expect people to have strong oppionions on the stuff I write or that they want to comment on my thoughts in any way.&#xA;And if there is someone who really wants to tell me how they feel about a certain topic, there is always my email address on the frontpage.&#xA;And there you have it. The reason I dont have comments enabled and why I probably will never turn them on.&#xA;Just putting this out there so I can reference it if somebody at some time should ask or wonder about it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
