<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>House on Tomas Tech Lab</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/house/</link>
    <description>Recent content in House on Tomas Tech Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 14:25:29 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/house/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>I made an Oopsie and PoE is not Wifi</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/i-made-an-oopsie-and-poe-is-not-wifi/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 14:25:29 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/i-made-an-oopsie-and-poe-is-not-wifi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Do you kow the feeling when you think you have figured out something but then you are completely wrong about it and then realize that if you had been more coreful in the first place you could have prevented it?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;That just happened to me.&#xA;Nothing big, just an oversight. An obvbious one.&#xA;As you might know (or not) I bought an old House a few years ago. And my mission with it is to make it smart. Piece by piece, little by little.&#xA;So far so good. I pull network cables, I configure appliances, add them to my Home Assistant Network&amp;hellip; and all works great.&#xA;Mostly, sometimes, if I care enough about it.&#xA;As I also run my own AI RIG at home I try to make it &amp;ldquo;understand&amp;rdquo; certain phrases and trigger speicif routines. But all that is beside the point.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A House From the 50s - but smart</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/a-house-from-the-50s-but-smart/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 13:02:14 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/a-house-from-the-50s-but-smart/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the beginning of 2023 I bought a house and was pretty happy about it.&#xA;The house wasnt anything special but it has enough rooms to house me, my wife and my daughter.&#xA;The biggest issue however was that the man that lived here before us was a heavy smoker. And I mean a real heavy smoker.&#xA;So the walls and all the interior was basically soaked in nicotin.&#xA;So the only reasonable thing to do was to rip out basically anything and replace it with something new and fresh.&#xA;While I planned on how to achieve a home that I can live in for longer than just a few years a thought came to mind which was&#xA;basically: Why not make it smart if I have to renovate everything anyway?&#xA;And so it started.&#xA;But first I had so clarify some things:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
