<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Work on Tomas Tech Lab</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/work/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Work on Tomas Tech Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 17:09:48 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/work/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The first Steps</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-first-steps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 17:09:48 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-first-steps/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I already wrote about my decision to start something fresh. Something new. Something fun.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;And today I did the first step for that. It does not seem much but from now on its real.&#xA;As I have to get everything in order with the German government because&amp;hellip; taxes I guess.&#xA;I started today by filing for a new tax ID and verified myself for a new bank account.&#xA;This is a very weird endeavor that someone that wants to start working in Germany needs to do.&#xA;The Country itself isn&amp;rsquo;t so bad I think.&#xA;But the bureaucratic hoops one has to go through just because he/she wants to work in this country is sometimes very ridiculous.&#xA;I just learned the other day that you are not allowed to create a company and work for 0 bucks just because you love what you do.&#xA;Okay 0 bucks would be very strange but even if you don&amp;rsquo;t earn as much as someone else (the finance department) decides you should, your company can get shut down.&#xA;I really don&amp;rsquo;t know why it is like this but its real and its somewhat nuts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Party-Pub to Office-Space</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/from-party-pub-to-office-space/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 11:11:07 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/from-party-pub-to-office-space/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Imagine the following: You have a small house on your property. Not a full house you can live in, more like a bigger garden shed or a small pool house (without the pool&amp;hellip;.yet).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Got it? Alright. This is what I am working with. Or better: This is where I am working in.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So far this small space was used as a party room / private pub. Including everything, you can image.&#xA;Fridge, Bar, Stools, Table&amp;hellip; and everything in a cozy pub like lighting.&#xA;Seemed nice and I really liked it, but it is time for something new.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Time for something new (again)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/time-for-something-new-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 17:01:33 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/time-for-something-new-again/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I guess its time for me to move on, because everything is fucked.&#xA;In terms of work and employment at least. But its not that easy for me.&#xA;Let me explain and start from the beginning:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Its 2018: I just lost my last job in a huge agency and was in between jobs when I decided that its time for me to do freelancing.&#xA;Being my own boss was something that always wanted. And now there was my oppoprtunity.&#xA;So I started as a freelancer. Asked the government for a tax id and started to work.&#xA;I was on my own, there was no plan b and as a motivation my wife just gave birth to our daughter.&#xA;But I had a blast. I worked with way more motivation that before and, what surprised me the most, I had fun.&#xA;Actual, real fun. I created stuff. I was creative in ways I never imagined. Heck, I even had a proper instagram account that I regularly used and published stuff on. And people who know me personally would never expect some kind of social media work from me.&#xA;It was a great time and I really enjoyed it.&#xA;Then, about a year later, I wanted to push it to the next level.&#xA;So I grabbed my best friend of that time and asked him if he wants to found an agency for webdevelopment with me.&#xA;He was hesitant at first but as me and him both could bring in customers from our previous work there should be no issue to get started and be profitable from day 0.&#xA;And so we began. We used the name that I already was working under (Codezilla IT-Consulting) and then we kept working, we grew as a company over the years and now, after around 6 years, we are about 10 people. It wasnt always easy but we managed to push through.&#xA;And all that without any venture capital or other sources of income.&#xA;It feels great.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A New Hope (kinda)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/a-new-hope-kinda/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 15:59:34 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/a-new-hope-kinda/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am on the brink of a new work related project. And at first glance there is no real issue with it.&#xA;I com to this conclusion because of a few factors:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;i am currently looking for work&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;the projects tech-stack perfectly fits my tech stack&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;i was able to talk to the people involved in the project&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;the payment is okay-ish&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;there is a perspective of future projects with that client&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This combination of facts makes it impossible for me to ignore it.&#xA;But there is something that makes my spidersense tingling. Nothing too big but it makes me be cautios of possible endeveaures.&#xA;I think its my 4. point, but maybe not for the reasons you might initially think.&#xA;The payment for my work is fixed. There is no more negotiation about that, so everything is alright&amp;hellip; right?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leaving a Government Project</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/leaving-a-government-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 19:00:54 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/leaving-a-government-project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Guess what happened.&#xA;I got &amp;ldquo;fired&amp;rdquo; from my government project. Well, its not really fired. I was on probation for 6 months and at the end of this 6 months they decided that I wasnt good enough (I guess??).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The thing is, I dont really know why the let me go.&#xA;I asked for reasons twice and didnt get an answer.&#xA;Its okay, from my side, as I didnt really liked the work and the environment anyway, but I would really like to know what&#xA;the real reason was that lead them to the decision that I have to leave.&#xA;Someone said it was due to my code quality or lack of standards, but in my (most likely biased) opinion.&#xA;There was no such thing as lacking code quality or lack of standards in my work.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Working for Governal It Suppliers</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/working-for-governal-it-suppliers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 10:09:30 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/working-for-governal-it-suppliers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In my 10+ years of working in the IT industry, I have worked for a number of government IT suppliers.&#xA;Wether it be government departments directly or suppliers or agencies for governement IT services.&#xA;I had some insight in how these parts of the government operate and why they do things the way they do.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I want to introduce this by saying that I have worked with these departments and agencies but still only had&#xA;insight in scoped projects. Which is a good thing on the one hand but means that everything I&amp;rsquo;m about to write here&#xA;needs to be taken with a grain of salt as all of this might not apply to other parts of government projects, agencies, suppliers etc.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
